Guide to the John F. Kennedy Presidential campaign materials, 1959-1960
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
John F. Kennedy Presidential campaign materials
1959-1960
M0561
Arnold, Maxwell
2 Linear feet
Please note that the media in this collection has been reformatted and 'use copies' exist for use in the Field Reading Room.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Maxwell Arnold, 1991
Information about Access
None.
Biography
Maxwell ("Bud") Arnold was a member of the San Francisco advertising agency, Guild, Basrom & Bonfigli, Inc., that handled the campaign publicity. The firm began in 1948 and in 1965 was bought out by a New York agency. The client for the campaign publicity was the Democratic National Committee. It was the first time television was used in a presidential campaign. Arnold was the principal script writer.
Scope and Content
Book of strategy, scripts, storyboards, memos, notes, six- minute film strip featuring Mrs. Kennedy, and 15 five-minute television commercials. All media for this collection has been reformatted.
Access Terms
Fonda, Henry; Kennedy, Jacqueline; Kennedy, John F., (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.
Collection Contents
- Series 1: Media
  - Debate Revisited VT-44-5M, 1 videotape(s): 2 in. (Box 1)
    Excerpts from famous first debate between Richard Nixon and Senator John F. Kennedy.
  - American Prestige No. 2, 1 videotape(s): 2 in. (Box 1)
    Composite of debates, speeches.
  - Victura VT-47-5M, 1 videotape(s): 2 in. (Box 1)
    Scenes of JFK and his sail boat. Never aired.
  - Questions & Answers. Dupe. VT-34-5M, 1 videotape(s): 2 in. (Box 1)
    Edited from press conferences, Meet the Press, Face the Nation.
  - Final Answer VT-45-5M Dupe, 1 videotape(s): 2 in. (Box 2)
    Senator Kennedy affirms once again that he believes in the separation of church and state.
  - Old Age, 1 videotape(s): 2 in. (Box 2)
  - Ouemoy-Matsou VT-14-5M [Quemoy-Matsu], 1 videotape(s) 2 in. (Box 2)
    Excerpts from NY speech, later withdrawn from campaign use.
  - GOP Leadership VT-40-5M, 1 videotape(s) 2 in. (Box 2)
  - Warm Springs VT-38-5M, 1 videotape(s) 2 in. (Box 3)
    Film features Kennedy's visit to Warm Springs, Georgia where he addresses healthcare.
  - American Prestige VT-35-5M Dupe., 1 videotape(s) 2 in. (Box 3)
    Revision of "National Prestige".
  - Jacqueline Kennedy VT-39-5M Dupe., 1 videotape(s) 16 mm. (Box 3)
    Video of Jacqueline Kennedy dated October 26, 1960. Actress Myrna Loy summarizes a recent interview Mrs. Kennedy gave to a TV program. Mrs. Kennedy addresses topics such as: raising her daughter Caroline according to Dr. Benjamin Spock's theories; missing Senator Kennedy while he was out campaigning; her attitudes towards campaigning; whether Senator Kennedy wanted a boy or a girl for the baby she was carrying; what she thought living in the White House would be like; did she think a First Lady influenced the life of the White House; and did she wish her husband was not so busy.
  - US Economy UT-41-5M, 1 videotape(s) 16 mm. (Box 3)
  - One VHS tape that includes two features: a) 6 minute film strip for CBS-TV half-hour special with Jacqueline Kennedy and b) 5 minute TV spot regarding Senator John F. Kennedy and the PT Boat story. Narrated by Henry Fonda, 1 videotape(s) 2 in. (Box 4)
    Six-minute film strip prepared for use in half-hour CBS-TV afternoon show featuring Mrs. Kennedy talking with Henry Fonda while photographs and home-movie film clips of JFK, Jackie, Caroline, friends play. Jack and Henry Fonda dialogue off camera. The PT boat segment was an adaptation of John Hersey's story of JFK's wartime heroism.
  - Domestic. Dupe VT-42-5M, 1 videotape(s) 2 in. (Box 4)
- Series 2: Various administrative records, including notes, memos, storyboards
  - Kennedy bumper sticker, Misc brochures on where the democratic party stood on different political issues, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1960 Democratic Fact book, sample copies and media marketing scripts, receipts for advertising space in Ebony Magazine (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Guild, Bascom & Bonfigli internal memos and notes regarding how to design the candidate’s marketing campaign (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Guild, Bascom & Bonfigli formal marketing campaign for the Democratic Presidential Campaign, July 1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Storyboards and television commercial scripts (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Storyboards and television commercial scripts featuring Jackie Kennedy, Senator Kennedy, and Henry Fonda, Fall 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Recommendations for strategy prior to the Democratic convention and nomination of Kennedy (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Official program from the 1960 Democratic National Convention (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Glass slides of storyboards (Box 5, Folder 9)